Our coding feels exhausting.
I mean, I think a lot of people are
feeling this way because
I think the main thing that I'm seeing
is that people are having to do so much
more strategic thinking than they used
to. Before, you would have these coding
sessions where you would write the code
and that was like a little break for
your brain. That's the kind of tactical
side where you're kind of on the ground
doing it sort of almost like non-verbal
reasoning, not having to think very
much, just sort of moving stuff around,
kind of playing a game almost. But now
all AI has just eaten that, right? AI
has eaten the tactical side of
programming. So, everything that we do
now is strategic thinking long-term. And
everything that we do, because we're
having to operate at a level above the
AI, think above the level that the AI is
operating at.
I mean, we've all turned into lead
developers. We've gone higher up the
chain and that demands high-level
thinking. I don't honestly know what we
do about this. I think it's just baked
into the loaf. Everyone who's using AI,
whether they're using it or anything
else, they're having their boring grunt
work taken away, but it means that their
brain is under so much more strain. I
have to say that I like it, you know, I
do like making high-level decisions, but
I end each day pretty knackered.